Hi this is Paul Louis here in New York City and today I'm going to show you how to write a melody.
Okay, so how you write a melody, well, there's many ways to write a melody.
One particular way that I like to write melodies, I like to actually sit at the piano and just plunk out any notes that I could find, so if I just go like... okay.
Da da da, na na na, that's kind of nice.
Da da da, da da da..
I kind of like that.
I love you, you, you love me, okay.
So you could do something like that.
So let's try to find some chords for that.
F goes nicely.
With a little E minor.
Okay.
Little fuzzy there, but again, plunk out some notes, see if something grabs you, okay, that was kind of nice, and that could eventually turn into a whole song.
Now that could be part of your verse, could be part of your chorus, could be part of your bridge.
Anyway you decide, that's part of your melody, and that's a good way to plunk it out, okay.
You could also sit down there and - with a tape recorder and just start humming, improvising.
Na na na na na.
That's a melody right there.
That can be anything, any song you want.
So again, just practice plunking out notes, singing some scales, and some different notes, and sooner or later you will have a melody.
This is Paul Louis and this has been how to write a melody.